https://www.manchester.anglican.org/privacy/

Contact
HomeAbout UsDiocesan VisionBishopsArchdeaconsCathedralFind a ChurchBaptisms, Weddings & Funeralsour Church SchoolsDiocesan Board of EducationKeep in TouchSupport for SchoolsSchool BuildingsAdmissions and AppealsRE CurriculumTrainingAcademiesSchool LifeEducational linksSpecial eventsLink with LahoreDiocesan DirectoryDiocesan StaffDiocesan RegistryGovernanceDiocesan Synod and Board of FinanceBishop's CouncilDeanery SynodsParochial Church CouncilsElectoral RollParish recordsContact usOur Faith in ActionGrowingFresh ExpressionsStepping Stones for GrowthChurch PlantingNurturingMore than SundayWaitingJusticeGenerationsGenerosityWitnessDoubtWorshipCreationForgivenessFriendshipCommunityInvitationSeven ShiftsServingFairtrade Interfaith NetworksOur Linked DiocesesPartnershipsEco DioceseWelcoming cycling to our churchesTowards net zero carbonChildren and Young PeopleChildrenYouth WorkCHILDREN CHANGING PLACESMental Health and WellbeingIsonenCommunications and Digital resourcesAudio FilesPrayerChaplaincyUniversity ChaplaincyDisability friendly churchRacial JusticeNews & EventsCalendarLatest NewsE-newsStories of faithDevelopment & TrainingVocationsFoundations for MinistryAuthorised Lay MinistryEucharistic AssistantsReadersCuratesContinuing Ministerial DevelopmentMinisterial development reviewSupport for ParishesCoronavirus SafeguardingCovid-19 Safeguarding AdvicePast Cases Review 2Safeguarding TrainingSafeguarding ToolkitSafer RecruitmentPolicies and GuidanceChurch buildingsMaintenance, repair and conservationAdapting for the futureHistoric BuildingsDAC and FacultiesGetting DAC adviceThe Faculty processFunding opportunitiesParish FinanceDigital GivingGrantsGift AidChurchwarden ResourcesPCC ResourcesParish administrationYour church in interregnumCelebration of a new ordained ministryData protectionPrivacy noticeMission Action PlanningSupport for ClergyClergy WellbeingSupport NetworksSABBATICALSPastoral Support during Coronavirus EmergencyParsonagesRetired clergySelf-Supporting MinistryLeading Life EventsTerms of ServiceClergy Admin
Home > Support for Parishes
> Data protection > Privacy notice
Privacy notice
Support for ParishesCoronavirus SafeguardingChurch buildingsParish FinanceChurchwarden ResourcesPCC ResourcesData protectionPrivacy noticeMission Action Planning
Privacy Notice how we use your information
1. Your personal data what is it?
Personal data relates to a living individual who can be identified from that data. Data for example can be a name, photograph, email address, bank details, posts on social networking websites, medical information, or a computer IP address. Identification can be by the data alone or in conjunction with any other information in the data controllers possession or likely to come into such possession. The processing of personal data is governed by the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).
2. Who are we?
Manchester Diocesan Board of Finance is a registered charity and the financial and administrative body for the Church of England in the Diocese of Manchester.
3. How do we process your personal data?
Manchester Diocesan Board of Finance complies with its obligations as a data controller under the GDPR by:
keeping personal data up to date;
storing and destroying it securely;
not collecting or retaining excessive amounts of data;
protecting personal data from loss, misuse, unauthorised access and disclosure; and
ensuring that appropriate technical measures are in place to protect personal data.
4. Why do we process your personal data?
We use your personal data for the following purposes:
To deliver our charitable aims which are to promote, facilitate and assist the work and purposes of the Church of England for the advancement of the Christian faith in the Diocese of Manchester and elsewhere and to provide a voluntary service for the benefit of the public;
To administer records of clergy, laity, parish, deanery, archdeaconry, diocesan, cathedral and synod members, officers, employees, volunteers and committees;
To fundraise and promote the interests of the Church of England and our charity;
To manage our employees and volunteers;
To maintain our own accounts and records (including the processing of gift aid applications);
To carry out comprehensive safeguarding procedures and checks in accordance with best safeguarding practice from time to time;
To inform you of news, events, activities, training and services running either within the Diocese of Manchester or further afield that are relevant to your role through mailings (by email and/or hard copy), and Enews (a subscription email service from which you can unsubscribe at any time).
5. What is the legal basis for processing your personal data?
Most processing is necessary for our legitimate interests or the legitimate interests of a third party (such as the Church Commissioners or another Church of England organisation)
We also process data to enable us to meet our legal, contractual and statutory obligations. Examples would be to operate our payroll function or to undertake disclosure and barring checks or to process your gift aid donations;
We can process information about your religious beliefs where that processing relates to members or former members (or those who have regular contact with it in connection with those purposes)and there is no disclosure to a third party without consent In all other instances your explicit consent will be obtained.
6. Sharing your personal data
Your personal data will be treated as confidential. We sometimes need to share the data we process with you and also with others. It will only be shared with third parties where it is necessary for the performance of our work or with your prior consent. We will need to share your data with some or all of the following:
The appropriate bodies of the Church of England including other data controllers such as the Bishop of Manchester or the National Church Institutions;
Our agents, servants and contractors.
Diocesan officers, bishops, archdeacons, officeholders and other clergy or lay persons nominated or licensed to support the mission of the Church of England in the Diocese.
Other persons or organisations operating within the Diocese of Manchester including, where relevant, the Manchester Diocesan Board of Education, the Dean and Chapter of Manchester Cathedral, the Diocesan Registry and the Chancellor of the Consistory Court for the Diocese of Manchester;
Educators and examining boards such as the All Saints Centre for Mission and Ministry
Statutory consultees such as Historic England
Crockfords Clerical Directory
Local and central government and statutory undertakers such as utility companies in respect of supplies of energy to a property.
7. How long do we keep your personal data?
We will keep some records permanently (such as minutes of our trustee meetings) or for an extended period of time if we are legally required to do so. For example HMRC require us to retain financial records for a minimum of seven years. We aim to keep data only for as long as is necessary and we may delete it when it is no longer needed.
8. Your rights and your personal data
Unless subject to an exemption under the GDPR, you have the following rights with respect to your personal data:
The right to request a copy of your personal data which we hold about you;
The right to request that we correct any personal data if it is found to be inaccurate or out of date;
The right to request your personal data is erased where it is no longer necessary for us to retain such data;
The right to withdraw your consent to the processing at any time, which you can easily do by email, in writing or by telephone using the contact details below;
The right to data portability which is to request that we provide you with your personal data and where possible, to transmit that data directly to another data controller;
The right, where there is a dispute in relation to the accuracy or processing of your personal data, to request a restriction is placed on further processing;
The right to object to the processing of personal data (where applicable);
The right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioners Office.
9. Further processing
If we wish to use your personal data for a new purpose, not covered by this Privacy Notice, then we will provide you with a new notice explaining this new use prior to commencing the processing and setting out the relevant purposes and processing conditions. Where and whenever necessary, we will seek your prior consent to the new processing.
10. Contact Details
To exercise all relevant rights and make queries or complaints please in the first instance contact the Data Protection Officer at: Church House, 90 Deansgate, Manchester M3 2GH Telephone: 0161 828 1400 Email: database@manchester.anglican.org
Alternatively, you can contact the Information Commissioners Office: Wycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire SK9 5AF Telephone: 0303 123 1113 Email: https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/email/
Facebook
Twitter
Instagram
YouTube
Flickr
ABOUT US
Diocesan Vision
Bishops
The Church of England Diocese of Manchester,
